Now, the ecosystem of data is no doubt impressive.
数据生态体系让人惊叹
So finding and using this information will become easier,
如果你了解数据收集流程
if you understand how the data collection process works.
如何找寻和使用数据就会变得更简单
Now, I'm sure it's no surprise to you that
我想大家其实都清楚
every action you take on the web is tracked one way or another.
我们每个人在网络上做出的任何举动都是被记录的
The pages you view,
浏览过的网页
the files you download,
下载过的文档
and even your demographic and interest data, is all recorded.
甚至你的个人信息、兴趣信息等 都被记录
At the 2018, Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas.
在 2018 年 拉斯维加斯举行的 Consumer Electronics展览上
Intel projected that by 2020,
Intel 曾经预测 在 2020 年
we will be generating 1.5 gigabytes of data
我们每个人每天能产生 1.5 千兆字节的网络数据
All of that tracking data we bought and sold by over
这些数据会在数据买卖方进行流通
4,000 data brokers in the United States alone.
仅在美国 就有超过 4000 多家数据买卖公司
Now, this data is collected as first,
这些数据又分为第一方数据（first party data）
second, and third party data.
第二方数据（second party data）以及 第三方数据（third party data）
First party data is what you collect,
第一方数据是指你自己收集到的数据
all the information that you immediately have access to,
你直接拥有的数据
information coming from your website,
比如你的网站数据
your subscriptions, and your CRM.
你的订阅数据 你的 CRM 数据
Now, second party data is essentially all of the first party data that is resold.
第二方数据是指被转手卖出的第一方数据
So if you collected data on your customers and sold that to someone else,
比如 如果你收集到了关于你的客户的信息 然后卖给了别人
it would then become second party data.
这就是第二方数据
This could include things such as your website data,
你可以卖你的网站数据
but it also goes as far as how people are
也可以卖关于客户如何使用你的应用的数据
using an application or even surveys that you run.
甚至你的调研结果
Finally, third party data.
最后 第三方数据
These are all the aggregators.
第三方数据是集大成者
Third-party data vendors by from all sorts of sources and then they combine this data.
第三方数据平台会从各个来源买入数据 然后整合这些数据
Now, this data is coming from a myriad of places.
对于如何收集数据 有几个来源
First, we have the cookies that follow you
首先 Cookies 会记录你的浏览路径
around or pixels that fire when you make a transaction,
然后有像素追踪、
and then we also have device fingerprinting,
设备指纹追踪
which is a really interesting method of combining information about you,
最后这个很有意思 能收集到很多信息
such as your location, screen size,
包括你的位置、屏幕大小、
the hardware using, plugins you have,
使用的硬件、插件、
apps you have, software, and so on.
应用、软件 等等
Because it's easy to guess whether or not you're
这样一来 即使你暂时离开你的手机或者电脑
the same person between two sessions on a site,
也很容易判定你是否是同一个人
because it's very unlikely that somebody else has
因为几乎不可能有两个人在设备上
that exact combination of items on their device.
有着完全一样的信息组合
In fact, your very own Internet service provider could be selling data about who you are,
事实上 你的网络供应商就可以贩卖你的信息
where you've been, and so on.
你是谁 你浏览过哪些网页 等等
So what can we do with this knowledge?
这些对我们来说有什么用呢?
Well, we know that we can layer in all of
我们可以把这些信息洞察加入
these additional insights into this traditionally flat information.
传统的信息收集
If you find a gap in your data and you want to fill it in to answer a question,
比如 你发现你的数据有个漏洞 只有补上漏洞才能解决问题
you now understand that this information is out there and you can find
那你现在就知道了 可以去找到这个数据
it and fill that it take Google Analytics, for example.
然后弥补 举个例子 我在使用 Google Analytics
Let's say I measure one visit to my website.
我在研究某个用户访问我的网站的行为
Now, that data point is interesting,
这个行为本身会产生一些数据
but there is a breadth of information behind it.
但其实有更多的数据可以提供给我们
Google can tell me characteristics such as where that clip came from,
Google 可以告诉我们一些数据 比如访问来源
how long that visit lasted,
访问时长
and the page that they were on.
访问的页面
Now, that's all first party information,
这些都是第一方信息
but dig deeper and you'll find that Google can bring me third party information,
但深入挖下去 你会发现 Google 也可以提供第三方信息
such as the visitor's interests,
比如访问者的兴趣爱好
their market segment, even their age range and gender.
他属于哪个细分市场 甚至年龄段 性别等
That data combined helps paint a much better picture of what's going on on my website.
综合这些信息能让我更好地了解我的网站表现
It tells me more about the type of people that are being exposed to my content,
比如接触到我的内容的是哪一类人群
and it can help me understand how to change my marketing behaviors.
也可以帮助我更好地改变我的市场策略
So as we layer that data together,
所以 当我们整合数据时
we can answer more complex questions and segment in ways that provide us richer insight.
我们可以回答一些很复杂的问题 获得更有价值的洞察